Jaison Binns

Phone: 610.348.4284 | Email: binns.jaison@live.com | Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/jaison-binns/ |

Portfolio: jaisonbinns.github.io/

Summary

Experienced, well-rounded developer, who focuses on the user-centered experience to deliver intuitive user features and applications to multiple clients to drive rapid business growth. Passionate, driven entrepreneur, who has self-learned many languages to launch a freelancing business.

Skills	Front End	Front End/Other	Other
•	React Redux • React Router • Redux Thunk •	jQuery Material/Semantic UI Bootstrap InVision/Figma Adobe Creative Suite Agile, Scrum Jest •	. ,

Experience

GoMoto, Inc. / Development/Operations

April 2019 - PRESENT, PHILADELPHIA, PA

- Created front end notification user feature for the client web dashboard using React.
- Automated operational data entry tasks using Python, BeautifulSoup, Selenium, and Excel.
- Compile, analyze and monitor product performance and data for clients exceeding revenue goals for over 75% of clients.
- Worked remotely as an agile team member focused on software delivery and support in a high growth small company.

Self-Employed / Freelance Developer

June 2020 - PRESENT, PHILADELPHIA, PA

• Created websites for a couple local restaurants, which increased pickup orders by 10% in June.

Vibespot App, LLC / UX/UI Designer

OCTOBER 2018 - APRIL 2019, PHILADELPHIA, PA

- Redesigned the 2.0 UX/UI experience using MS Paint and InVision resulting in 2,000+ app downloads and 10+ venue and collegiate partnerships over 5 months.
- Provided strategic user stories/issues as a Agile team member based on measured, compiled user feedback.
- Worked as a founding member with a remote development team based in Ukraine.
- Analyzed user data to develop a new strategic business plan resulting in decreased new user acquisition cost from \$5/user to \$2/user.

Education